# **BRIGHT IORTSOR**

## FRONTEND ENGINEER

Frontend Developer with over 1.5 years of experience developing and maintaining user friendly web applications. Proficient in frontend technologies such as React, Javascript, Typescript, CSS3, Tailwind, MUI, Git and GitHub with a strong understanding of responsive design and performance optimization. Excellent communication and problem solving skills developed over years of related work experience.

# **Work History**

## 01/2023-Current

# Frontend Engineer

### Moonsat Technology, Abuja, FCT

- Developed front-end code for various client projects
- Wrote code to create responsive layouts for websites
- Implemented designs using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React and Typescript.
- Worked with designers and back-end developers to create cohesive user experiences
- Optimized the website for speed and turnover.

# 08/2022-01/2023

### **Frontend Developer**

#### Kinatech Innovative, Abuja, FCT

- Developing responsive web applications with modern Javascript frameworks like React and Vue.
- Monitor and report on key metrics such as page load, time to interact and conversion rates to identify areas of improvement.
- Implementing search engine optimization and improving business reach by 50%.
- Learning and adopting new techniques to improve web security and overall user interface and frontend architecture.

# 04/2022 -Current

# Frontend Engineer

#### AltSchool Africa, Remote.

 Lead the development and implementation of responsive web application to ensure compatibility across all screens using React.js and Vue.js frameworks.

# Contact

#### Address

Abuja, Nigeria

#### **Phone**

+234 (0) 7038501811

#### E-mail

iortsor@gmail.com

#### **Portfolio**

https://biortsor.live

#### LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/brightiortsor

# **Skills**

Networking



Creativity



Critical Thinking



Communication



Teamwork



**Technical Writing** 



- Collaborate with designers and backend engineers to define, design and ship new features thus creating a seamless user experience and improving conversion rates by at least 30%.
- Write unit and integration tests to ensure quality and reliability of code.

#### Frontend Engineer 01/2022 -05/2022

#### Side Hustle, Remote

- Developed and maintained the user interface of web applications.
- Integrated enhancements into web design to improve user stickiness, smooth functionality and boost load times.
- Worked closely with designers and backend engineers to ensure seamless user experience.
- Continuously improved the performance, usability and accessibility of web applications.

#### **Customer Service Executive** 07/2021 -08/2022 NISA Premier, Abuja, Nigeria

- Provided company information and policies to customers upon inquiry and answered questions via phone, email or online chat.
- Escalated critical customer issues to supervisor to avoid lost revenue and canceled policies.
- Made reasonable procedure exceptions to accommodate unusual customer requests.
- Provided primary customer support to internal and external customers.
- Clarified customer issues and determined root cause of problems to resolve product or service complaints.

# Education

2013-03 -Bachelor of Technology: Microbiology

2018-10 Federal University of Technology - Minna, Nigeria

Second Class Upper (4.49 cgpa)

2009-09 -Senior School Certificate 2012-07

Government Secondary School - Abuja, Nigeria

# **Technologies**

- Javascript(ES6)
- React.js
- **Typescript**
- Vue.is
- **CSS**
- **Tailwind**
- **Bootstrap**
- SCSS/SASS
- **Ant Design**
- Material UI
- HTML5
- Git
- **GitHub**